Guide to the Apple Computer, Inc. Ephemera collection, 1978 - 1998
Department of Special Collections
Apple Computer, Inc. ephemera collection,
1978 - 1998
M0825
Apple Computer, Inc.
9 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
This collection contains annual reports, internal communications, corporate communications, engineering reports, manuals, product information files, catalogs, price lists, Apple publications, human resource information, conference and workshop information, software, hardware, and corporate memorabilia.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions on access.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Henry Lowood, 1995-1997, and Wynne Dobyns, 1995-2002.
Provenance
Some of the materials in this artificial collection were transferred from M0443, the Silicon Valley Ephemera Collection, to create an Apple Computer-specific collection and integrated into a previously-existing artificial collection of Apple Computer materials.
Biography
Apple Computer, Inc. was incorporated on January 3, 1977. Apple Computer, Inc., ignited the personal computer revolution in the 1970s with the Apple II, and reinvented the personal computer in the 1980s with the Macintosh, of which it had sold more 30 million systems as of the end of 1998. Apple's original mission as articulated by its co-founder Steven Jobs was to bring the best personal computing products and support to students, educators, designers, scientists, engineers, business persons and consumers in over 140 countries around the world. In 1998, Apple Computer, Inc. maintained Research & Development sites in Cork, Ireland; Cupertino, California; Tokyo, Japan; and Zhuhai, China. Apple owned manufacturing facilities in the United States, Ireland, and Singapore. Distribution facilities are located in the United States, Europe, Canada, Australia, Singapore, and Japan.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
Contains annual reports, internal communications, corporate communications, engineering reports, manuals, product information files, catalogs, price lists, Apple publications, human resource information, conference and workshop information, software, hardware, and corporate memorabilia.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Corporate culture.; Science--History.
Collection Contents
- Series 1. Corporate Communications
  - Annual report, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual report, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Annual report, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual report, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Annual report, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annual report, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Annual report, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Annual shareholders meeting materials, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Annual shareholders meeting materials, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Apple Computer logo, signature, and typeface standards (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Apple facts, 1994 - 1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Apple facts, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Apple Teaching Fellows directory, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Apple Technical web sites (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - At the crossroads: a strategic framework for a renewed Apple / Dr. Gil Amelio. -- 1996 May (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Authorized dealers (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Building the future of learning technologies (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Go figure: a quick look at some important facts, 1996 - 1997 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Living in the world we've changed (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Macintosh operating system strategy (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Marketing flyers (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Masters of Media program (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Product registration (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Rebates (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Sharing our two most valuable resources (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Year 200 readiness disclosure statement (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Apple put their brightest engineers....Advertising supplement to the Wall Street Journal25 Feb. 1993 (Box 15)
  - Dear Apple Customers, I would like to....The Wall Street Journal17 April 1997 (Box 15)
  - Dream Big: The big paper about ideas, college, and Macintosh. (Box 15)
  - only apple, San Jose Mercury News10 April 1997 (Box 15)
  - Vous voulez un Macintosh ou un simple ordinateur? (Box 15)
  - What would you think of a computer....Advertising supplement to the Wall Street Journal, 2 items (Box 15)
- Series 2. Apple Developer Group
  - Apple Developer University (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Macintosh development (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Series 3. Product Information
  - Airport (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Apple, general (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Apple II (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Apple II communications interface card (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Apple II parallel printer interface card (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Apple IIe (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - AppleTalk (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - CD-ROM drive (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Disk II (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Displays (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - eWorld (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Fire Wire (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - iBook (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - iMac (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Lisa (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Mac OS 8.5 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Macintosh (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Macintosh IIfx (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Macintosh IIx press kit (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Macintosh SE (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Macintosh software (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Newton (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - PhotoFlash (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Power Book G3 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Power Macintosh (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Power Mac G3 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Power Mac G4 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Power PC (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Power School (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Print Shop (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - QuickTime Media Layer (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - System 7 Pro (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Workgroup servers (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Third party: Adobe (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Third party: MicroRain (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Third party: Mountain Hardware (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Third party: Warp Nine (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Series 4. Catalogs and price lists
  - Apple gift catalog (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Starting line: Apple Marketing communications catalog, 1987 Mar. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Suggested retail price list, 1978 - 1979 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Series 5. Manuals
  - Apple II 80-column text card manual: for IIe only (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Apple II Extended 80-column text card manual: for IIe only (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Apple II Apple 6502 assembler / editor (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Apple II Apple Fortran language reference manual (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Apple II Apple how to! (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Apple II Apple II business graphics (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Apple II Apple II monitor peeled (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Apple II Apple Pascal language reference manual (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Apple II Apple Pascal update (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Apple II addendum to the Apple Pascal language reference manual (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Note: in same folder as related operating system reference manual
  - Apple II addendum to the Apple Pascal operating system reference manual (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Note: in same folder as related language reference manual
  - Apple II Apple SuperPILOT editor's manual (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Apple II Apple SuperPILOT language reference manual (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Apple II Applesoft tool kit (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Apple II Appleworks tutorial (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Apple II Backup II (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Apple II Cable and connectors guide (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Apple II The DOS manual (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Apple II DOS programmer's manual: for II, II+, IIe (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Apple II ICE user manual for Apple II and III (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Apple II IEEE-488 interface user's guide (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Apple II Pascal ProFile manager manual: for II, II+, IIe (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Apple II ProDOS user's manual (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Apple II Quick File II .. an introduction (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Apple II Quickfile II: for IIe only, Pascal 1.1 based (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Apple II reference manual, 1978 Jan. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Apple II WPL manual: for IIe only, DOS 3.3 based (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Apple IIe design guidelines (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Apple IIe Guide to the new features (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Apple IIe owner's manual, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Apple II Parallel printer interface card (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Apple II serial interface card installation and operation manual (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Revised Apple IIe technical reference manual: final draft/ Steven Ford High (1 of 2), May 1986 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Revised Apple IIe technical reference manual: final draft/ Steven Ford High (2 of 2), May 1986 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Apple III CP/M Reference Manual (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Apple III daisy wheel printer user's manual. Part II: guide to Apple III (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Apple III Microsoft BASIC reference manual (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Apple III OEM prototyping card (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Apple III Pascal introduction, filer, and editor, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Apple III Pascal Numerics Manual: a guide to using the Apple III Pascal SANE and Elems units (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Apple III Pascal program preparation tools (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Apple III Pascal program preparation tools errata (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Apple III Pascal Programmer's Manual, vol. 1 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Apple III Pascal Programmer's manual, vol. 2 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Apple III Pascal technical reference manual (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Apple III Pascal technical reference manual: supplement (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Apple III Profile owner's manual (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Apple III serial card III (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Apple III Soft Card III installation and operation manual, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Apple III SOS device driver writer's guide (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Dylan: an object-oriented dynamic language/ Apple Computer Eastern Research and Technology (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Macintosh Plus (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Macintosh Manual (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Apple Macintosh User's handbook (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Macintosh SE: [manual], 1987 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Macintosh SE/30. Special features of your Macintosh SE/30, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Novations Modems (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Series 6. Publications
  - Apple Library Users Group Newsletter: vol. 2 no. 2-4; vol. 3 no. 1-2, 4; vol. 4 no. 1-4; vol. 5 no. 1-3; vol. 6 no. 1-4; vol. 7 no. 1-3May 1984 - July 1989, 20 newsletters (Box 9)
  - Apple Library Users Group Newsletter: vol. 7 no. 4; vol. 8 no. 1-2October 1989 - April 1990, 3 newsletters (Box 10)
  - 5-Star News, 1994 Sept. - Dec. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - 5-Star News, 1995 Jan. - June (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - 5-Star News, 1995 July - Dec. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - 5-Star News, 1996 Jan. - Dec./ 1997 Jan (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Apple Directions, 1997 Jan. - July (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Apple Education News (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Apple: the personal computer magazine and catalog, vol. 1, no. 1-2 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Contact, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Contact 5 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Inside Apple, vol. 2, no. 2 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Rubin, Charles. The Macintosh Bible "what do I do now?" book (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Williams, Robin. The Mac in not a typewriter (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Joint Venture: Silicon Valley, an economy of risk (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Apple Media Arts SupplementsWinter 1999- Spring 1999, 3 items (Box 15)
  - Apple Media Arts: vol. 1 no. 1-2, vol. 2 no. 1Spring 1998 - Winter 1999, 4 items (Box 15)
  - Apple Outlook1997 Jan, 1997 May, 3 items (Box 15)
  - Apple Product Line1997 Jan, 1997 May, 3 items (Box 15)
- Series 7. Clippings and articles
  - San Jose Mercury News article re: Heidi Roizen, 1996 Dec. 8 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - San Mateo County Times, Apple turns 20, faces a tough road ahead/ Catalina Ortiz1996 April (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Time Magazine, Apple's new core: how Steve Jobs made a sleek machine that could be the home-digital hub of the future/ by Josh Quittner2002 Jan. 14 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - The Lists: The Business Journal Serving San Jose and the Silicon Valley, 1995 Addendum30 Jan. 1995 (Box 15)
  - Who's Who in High-Tech: A directory of high-ranking executives in Silicon Valley1995 Feb. (Box 15)
- Series 8. Apple Library
  - Apple Library brochure (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Apple Library of Tomorrow proceedings, 1990-1992 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Series 9. Conferences and workshops
  - Hyperfest (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Mactivity '961996 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - MacWorld Exposition San Francisco, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Troubleshooting and maintaining the Macintosh, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Series 10. Staff development, benefits, etc.
  - Apple Health and Fitness (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Apple Lambda (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Apple Staff Development, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - The Company Store (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Compensation and benefits (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Learn and Earn Program (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Take our Daughters to Work Day, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Series 11. Photographs
  - Apple Emplyees surrounding Macintosh (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Series 12. Ephemera
  - eWorld mousepad (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - stickers (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Why do you suppose those folks in Redmond try so hard to imitate us?, marketing kit (Box 15)
- Series 13. Computer files
  - Macintosh 68000 Developments System, software box (Box 13)
  - Apple presents...Apple: IIe version (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Apple IIe business applications simulation (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Quick File II: program and Quick File II: sample files (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - List of diskettes (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Examples 5/85 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - eWorld (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Mac Build Disk 2/85 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Mac Build Disk 5/85 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - MacStuff 1/85 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - MacStuff 2/85 (copy 1) (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - MacStuff 2/85 (copy 2) (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - MacStuff 5/85 (copy 1) (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - MacStuff 5/85 (copy 2) (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Mac Supplement 1/85 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Mac Supplement 2/85 (copy 1) (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Mac Supplement 2/85 (copy 2)(1-4 of 6) (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Mac Supplement, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Mac Works, 1985 Jan. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Mac Works XL 3.0,1985 May (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Workshop Supplement, 1985 May (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Workshop 3.9 update, 1985 May (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Stepping into the future...Robert's day with the Mac OS (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - The 1997 Apple MacAdvocate CD-ROM (Box 14, Folder 15)
Related Collections
Apple Computer, Inc.
Records M1007
An online guide to the Apple Computer, Inc. Records is available as an XML document at: http://www-sul.stanford.edu/depts/spc/xml/m1007.xml and as an HTML document at: http://www.oac.cdlib.org/dynaweb/ead/stanford/mss/m1007/
Silicon Valley Ephemera Collection M0443
An online guide to the Silicon Valley Ephemera Collection is available as an XML document at: http://www-sul.stanford.edu/depts/spc/xml/m0443.xml and as an HTML document at: http://www.oac.cdlib.org/dynaweb/ead/stanford/mss/m0443/